const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"While examining the lateral view of the X-ray of the skull, a radiologist points out a region that is the meeting point of the parietomastoid, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What point is he referring to?","answers":[{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The rhombencephalic isthmus separates which parts of the brain?","answers":[{"option":"Mesencephalon from the metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Myelencephalon from the spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Rhombencephalon from the mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon from the myelencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Prosencephalon from the diencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Where does the aqueous humor drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Scleral venous sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Sigmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Sagittal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The gland that secretes calcitonin is formed from which pharyngeal pouch?","answers":[{"option":"5th","bool":false},{"option":"1st","bool":false},{"option":"3rd","bool":false},{"option":"4th","bool":true},{"option":"2nd","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following ions moves from endolymph to stereocilia to depolarize the hair cells?","answers":[{"option":"K+","bool":true},{"option":"Mg2+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false},{"option":"Ca2+","bool":false},{"option":"Na+","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Sensory retina develops from which part of the optic cup?","answers":[{"option":"Pars optica retinae","bool":true},{"option":"Pars caeca retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars iridica retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Outer layer of the optic cup","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Pterygoid venous plexus is a network of veins that drains into which of the following vein?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The swallowing center is located in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Taste fibres from circumvallate papillae pass through what nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which is not present in the carotid sheath?","answers":[{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External jugular vein","bool":true},{"option":"Common carotid artery","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which muscle takes part in the formation of palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Musculus uvulae","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following equalizes the pressure between the external atmosphere and the middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Auricle","bool":false},{"option":"External ear","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Pinna","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What happens to the vocal cords while swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Opened","bool":false},{"option":"Gapped by membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Approximated","bool":true},{"option":"No change","bool":false},{"option":"Overlapped","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A teacher discussed a fossa inferior and deep to the zygomatic arch and posterior to the maxilla. The appropriate fossa being discussed is?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygopalatine","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cranial","bool":false},{"option":"Infratemporal","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which nucleus of the thalamus is responsible for carrying fibers to the auditory cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Venteroposterolateral nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsomedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Ventroposteromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is a content of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"3rd part of the maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"2nd part of maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of the maxillary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What is the position of the macula lutea relative to the optic disc in the eyeball?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":true},{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Anesthesia in retromolar fossa primarily blocks which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Mental nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Fracture of mandible most likely results in the damage of which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Lingual nerve","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with complaints of dryness of nose and palate. Which ganglion must be damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygopalatine ganglion","bool":true},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Nodose ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary ganglion","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which type of gland is the gland of Zeis?","answers":[{"option":"Mucus glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified lacrimal glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sebaceous glands","bool":true},{"option":"Mebomian glands","bool":false},{"option":"Modified sweat glands","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is true about the canal of Schlemm?","answers":[{"option":"It is lined by stratified squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"It contains red cells","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"It communicates with the vitreous chamber","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Ethmoidal bulla can be seen in the middle nasal meatus. Which of the following is related to ethmoidal bulla?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal sinus","bool":true},{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ethmoidal sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Nasolacrimal duct drains tears to which of the following parts of the nose?","answers":[{"option":"Superior nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal sac","bool":false},{"option":"Middle nasal meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior nasal conchae","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal meatus","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following structures is present on the medial wall of the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Oval window","bool":true},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Epitympanic recess","bool":false},{"option":"Pyramidal process","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is not present on the lateral wall of the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Round window","bool":true},{"option":"Epitympanic recess","bool":false},{"option":"Handle of malleus","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Attachment of tensor tympani","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which muscle is not supplied by the hypoglossal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Styloglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The posterior arch of which cervical vertebra has a groove for the vertebral artery?","answers":[{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following cervical vertebrae is atypical?","answers":[{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C6","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C7","bool":true}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following features is not a characteristic of a typical cervical vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Triangular vertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Costal facets","bool":true},{"option":"Foramina transversarium","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Uncinate process on the body","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is bound by both the anterior and the posterior belly of the digastric muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Omoclavicular triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The anterior triangle of the neck is bound by which of the following posteriorly?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior border of sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Posterior border of sternocleidomastoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Superior belly of omyhyoid muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly of digastric muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly of digastric muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The two bellies of the digastric muscle have different embryological origins. What is true about the innervation of the muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior belly is innervated by V2","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior belly is innervated by V1","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V3","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V1","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior belly is innervated by V2","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The pterygopalatine fossa communicates with the orbit through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pterygomaxillary fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":true},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Optic canal","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The pterygopalatine fossa is bound anteriorly by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomatic process","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"At what level is the isthmus of the thyroid gland present?","answers":[{"option":"4th, 5th, and 6th tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"3rd, 4th, and 5th tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"1st, 2nd, and 3rd tracheal rings","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique line of the thyroid cartilage till the 6th tracheal ring","bool":false},{"option":"2nd, 3rd, and 4th tracheal rings","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The sternocleidomastoid muscle divides the neck into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Submental and submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and posterior triangles","bool":true},{"option":"Carotid and submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Submental and carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular and suboccipital triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A patient developed winging of the scapula after deep cervical lymph node biopsy. Which nerve is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Accessory spinal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A surgeon noticed bleeding from the pharynx while removing adenoids from a 13-year-old child. Which artery supplies the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior alveolar artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The second part of the maxillary artery travels between the heads of which muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Digastric muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Medial pterygoid muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which artery's main trunk is divided into mandibular, pterygoid, and pterygopalatine parts?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial temporal artey","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is not a part of the deep cervical fascia?","answers":[{"option":"Pretracheal fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Prevertebral fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":true},{"option":"Investing layer","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid sheath","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following structures pierces the buccinator muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual artery","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid or Stenson's duct","bool":true},{"option":"Deep facial vein","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which nerve divides into branches in the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 25-year-old presented to the emergency with stab wound in the neck at the submandibular triangle and tongue deviation. Which nerve is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A surgeon wants to remove a benign swelling from the tip of the nose of a patient under local anesthesia. Which nerve is blocked to anesthise the external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Infraorbital","bool":false},{"option":"Opthalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A patient came to the otorhinolaryngologist with the complaint of difficulty opening the mouth. Diagnosis of infection of the infratemporal fossa was made. The muscle of mastication occupying most of the upper part of the fossa that helps in opening the mouth was affected. What is the affected muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The nerve that supplies the muscles of mastication and is a part of the infratemporal fossa passes through which foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen stylomastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Emissary sphenoid foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The upper border of the mandible is thin and is surrounded by two processes; coronoid process anteriorly and condyloid process posteriorly. The two processes are separated by which deep cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular notch","bool":true},{"option":"Lingula","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar process","bool":false},{"option":"Mental foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular foramen","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What is the structure present on the anterior surface of the mandible through which inferior alveolar nerve and vessels pass called?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Mandibular notch","bool":false},{"option":"Mental foramen","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar process","bool":false},{"option":"Condylar process","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What is the dense fibrous connective tissue joint present between the frontal and the parietal bone called?","answers":[{"option":"Sagittal","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenofrontal","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Lambdoidal","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What is the thinnest part on the lateral wall of the skull where the anteroinferior corner of the parietal bone articulates with the greater wing of the sphenoid bone called?","answers":[{"option":"Pterion","bool":true},{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false},{"option":"Supramastoid crest","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid humulus","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What foramen is formed by the irregular medial end of the petrous part of the temporal bone, the greater wing of the sphenoid bone, and the basilar part of the occipital bone?","answers":[{"option":"Rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Lacerum","bool":true},{"option":"Jugular","bool":false},{"option":"Ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Spinosum","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which artery supplies the maxillary sinus and the maxillary incisors?","answers":[{"option":"Deep temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior superior alveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior alveolar","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 20-year-old male was brought to the emergency because of a wound on the scalp from a sharp object which was bleeding continuously. Bleeding from the scalp is always profuse due to what reason?","answers":[{"option":"Vessel wall fails to retract","bool":true},{"option":"Wound gape","bool":false},{"option":"Scalp is highly vascular","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels lie just beneath the skin","bool":false},{"option":"Large arteries lie in the pericranium","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Between which layers does the movement of the scalp take place?","answers":[{"option":"Pericranium and epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Skin and subcutaneous fat","bool":false},{"option":"Pericranium and loose areolar tissue","bool":true},{"option":"Skin and epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pericranium and skull","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which artery exits the middle cranial fossa through the optic canal?","answers":[{"option":"Labyrinthine","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal","bool":false},{"option":"Deep temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Opthalamic","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial temporal","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following describes the mucosa of the hard palate?","answers":[{"option":"Non-keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands posteromedially","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands anteroinferiorly","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and has submucosa and minor salivary glands posterolaterally","bool":false},{"option":"Keratinized and lacks submucosa and minor salivary glands","bool":true},{"option":"Non-keratinized and lacks submucosa and minor salivary glands","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is lined by small cuboidal cells in the duct system of the salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Intercalated duct","bool":true},{"option":"Interlobular duct","bool":false},{"option":"Intralobular duct","bool":false},{"option":"Striated duct","bool":false},{"option":"Main salivary duct","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What is true regarding the sublingual salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Minor gland","bool":false},{"option":"Mucus gland","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed gland","bool":true},{"option":"Serous gland","bool":false},{"option":"Present at the root of the tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The muscle that retracts the temporomandibular joint develops from which structure?","answers":[{"option":"2nd pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"What results from the failure of the fusion of maxillary prominence with the lateral nasal prominence?","answers":[{"option":"Median cleft lip","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral oblique cleft lip","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft ovula","bool":false},{"option":"Oblique facial cleft","bool":true},{"option":"Cleft palate","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The posterior one-third of the tongue develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypopharyngeal eminence","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral lingual swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottal swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Copula","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculum impar","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A patient visited an eye outpatient department with the complaint of loss of right field of vision in both eyes. Which of the following is damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Right optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Left optic tract","bool":true},{"option":"Left optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false},{"option":"Right optic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The magnocellular layer of the lateral geniculate body is concerned with which visual information?","answers":[{"option":"Greater spacial resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Lower temporal resolution","bool":false},{"option":"Color vision","bool":false},{"option":"Black-and-white vision","bool":true},{"option":"Discriminating fine details","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A group of researchers wanted to identify substances which require charged ions for taste receptor stimulation. The charged ions can be a combination of which tastes?","answers":[{"option":"Bitter and sour","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and umami","bool":false},{"option":"Salty and sour","bool":true},{"option":"Sweet and sour","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet and umami","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A high taste threshold in smokers is due to damage to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Taste center in cerebral cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Nerve fibers carrying taste sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitarius","bool":false},{"option":"Internal damage to papilla","bool":true},{"option":"External damage to taste buds","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which area of the cerebral cortex is responsible for the conscious perception, discrimination and analysis of odor?","answers":[{"option":"Amygdala","bool":false},{"option":"Hippocampus","bool":false},{"option":"Prepyriform cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Orbitofrontal cortex","bool":true}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A patient lost his ability to smell. Which cells in his nasal mucosa were most likely damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial","bool":false},{"option":"Multipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar","bool":true},{"option":"Unipolar","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudo unipolar","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which center of the brain controls the rapid directional movement of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Suprachiasmatic nucleus of the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Paraventricular nucleus of the hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pretectal nuclei in the midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral lateral geniculate nucleus of the thalamus","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 35-year-old male presents to the clinic with a decrease in near vision while distant vision is normal. Retinoscopy at 1-meter shows that he requires spherical lens for the correction of vision. Which error of refraction is present in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A child presents with difficulty in seeing the blackboard while sitting at the benches at the back in school. What is the most likely cause of his condition?","answers":[{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Myopia is most commonly caused by an increase in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thickness of the lens","bool":false},{"option":"Anteroposterior diameter of the eyeball","bool":true},{"option":"Viscosity of vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Thickness of the cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Viscosity of aqueous humor","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 44-year-old man visits his ophthalmologist with the complaint of increasing difficulty in reading the newspaper. His vision problem is due the inability to contract which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Extraocular muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Suspensory ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"Radial muscles of the iris","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Light energy activates rhodopsin which is a key process in phototransduction. What is the activated form of rhodopsin that excites electrical changes in the rods?","answers":[{"option":"Metarhodopsin-II","bool":true},{"option":"11-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Metarhodopsin-I","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 54-year-old man was operated for neuronal tumor at the base of the brain. He complained of visual field defect postoperatively. Brain MRI showed lesion in the right optic tract. Which visual field defect is present in the patient?","answers":[{"option":"Binasal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Right homonymous hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left homonymous hemianopia","bool":true},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopia","bool":false},{"option":"Left sided anopia","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A second year MBBS student performed experiments related to the sense of taste in the physiology lab. Which of the following taste sensation will have the lowest stimulation threshold?","answers":[{"option":"Sour","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter","bool":true},{"option":"Sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Acid","bool":false},{"option":"Salty","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Rhodopsin is a conjugated protein present in the rods of the retina. What is its composition?","answers":[{"option":"Opsin and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Keratin and 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Crystalline and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Crystalline and 11-cis-retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Opsin and 11-cis-retinal","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Most infants are born with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Emmetropia","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false},{"option":"Amblyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Astigmatism","bool":false},{"option":"Hypermetropia","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The five broad personality traits described by theory are extraversion, agreeableness, openness, conscientiousness, and neuroticism. Personality evaluation of Ali indicates that he has the tendency to be responsible, hard-working, goal-directed, organized and to adhere to norms and rules. Based on the findings, Ali must have scored high on which scale of big five personality test?","answers":[{"option":"Agreeableness","bool":false},{"option":"Extraversion","bool":false},{"option":"Openness","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroticism","bool":false},{"option":"Conscientiousness","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following muscles forms the roof of the suboccipital triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Rectus capitis posterior minor","bool":false},{"option":"Semispinalis capitis","bool":true},{"option":"Obliquus capitis inferior","bool":false},{"option":"Rectus capitis posterior major","bool":false},{"option":"Obliquus capitis superior","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The duct of the largest salivary gland, which forms a major part of salivary secretions, opens into which of the following regions of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Caruncula","bool":false},{"option":"Side of the lingual frenulum","bool":false},{"option":"Floor of the mouth","bool":false},{"option":"Opposite to second maxillary molar tooth","bool":true},{"option":"Sublingual fossa","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The pharyngeal plexus lies on which of the following muscles of the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Superior pharyngeal constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle pharyngeal constrictor","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior pharyngeal constrictor","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following cervical vertebrae has an odontoid process?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":true},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C7","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 44-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with a progressive loss of temporal field of vision. Visual field testing confirms bitemporal hemianopia. When compressed, which of the following structures is most likely to result in this defect?","answers":[{"option":"Visual cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":true},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiations","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following types of receptors is the taste receptor characterized as?","answers":[{"option":"Osmoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanoreceptor","bool":false},{"option":"Baroreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Pacinian corpuscles","bool":false},{"option":"Chemoreceptor","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 32-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with the complaint of excessive droopiness of the left eyelid (ptosis). Loss of function of which of the following muscles can result in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Levator palpebrae superioris","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A soldier hears the sound of gunshots and follows in the direction of the sound. Which of the following structures is responsible for the detection of the direction from which the sound is coming?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral superior olivary nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Cochlear nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Medial superior olivary nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries is located in the suboccipital triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Third part of vertebral artery","bool":true},{"option":"Suboccipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior auricular artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of basilar artery","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 59-year-old male patient presents to the ophthalmology clinic with a complaint of double vision. On evaluation, it is found that the muscle responsible for lateral rotation of the eye is paralyzed. Which of the following nerves innervates this muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A school counselor observes a student who works really hard and is highly ambitious toward his goal, but he can be very competitive and self-critical. In certain situations, he also tends to be impatient and shows anger management issues. Which of the following personality types is this student most likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Type B","bool":false},{"option":"Type D","bool":false},{"option":"Type A","bool":true},{"option":"Type C","bool":false},{"option":"Type E","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following landmarks in the skull of an adult marks the location of the posterior fontanelle in neonates?","answers":[{"option":"Asterion","bool":false},{"option":"Lambda","bool":true},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false},{"option":"Nasion","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following types of glands are the major salivary glands categorized under?","answers":[{"option":"Simple tubuloacinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Compound acinar gland","bool":false},{"option":"Compound tubular glands","bool":false},{"option":"Simple acinar glands","bool":false},{"option":"Compound tubuloacinar glands","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The maxillary artery which is embedded in the parotid gland supplies the deep tissue of the face. It is a terminal branch of which of the following arteries?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Pituitary adenomas can result in compression of the pituitary stalk. Which of the following is the most likely indication of compression of the pituitary stalk?","answers":[{"option":"Headache","bool":false},{"option":"Increased serum ADH","bool":false},{"option":"Vomiting","bool":false},{"option":"Memory loss","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperprolactinemia","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The superior oblique muscle is supplied by which of the following cranial nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Superior branch of oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior branch of oculomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the anterior wall of the external acoustic meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auriculotemporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Auricular branch of vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following muscles of facial expression is involved in smiling?","answers":[{"option":"Levator labi superioris","bool":false},{"option":"Risorius","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticus major","bool":true},{"option":"Levator anguli oris","bool":false},{"option":"Corrugator supercilii","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The philtrum of the upper lip is derived from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"Frontonasal prominence and maxillary prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence and lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral nasal prominence and medial nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Medial nasal prominence and maxillary prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence only","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A 36-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with an infection of the nasal and paranasal sinuses. He complains of a headache and vision problems. A CT scan reveals cavernous sinus thrombosis. Which of the following veins is the most likely route of spread of infection from the area around the nose and upper lips to the cavernous sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Supraorbital vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Infraorbital vein","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear vein","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A greater palatine nerve block will anesthetize which of the following areas of the oral cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Buccal gingivae of molars","bool":false},{"option":"Palatal mucosa and lingual gingivae anterior to maxillary canine teeth","bool":false},{"option":"Palatal mucosa and lingual gingivae posterior to maxillary canine teeth","bool":true},{"option":"Palatine mucosa only","bool":false},{"option":"Buccal gingivae of premolars","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following layers of the scalps contains the blood vessels supplying the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Pericranium","bool":false},{"option":"Epicranial aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":false},{"option":"Loose areolar connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Congenital aphakia results when an important structure of the eye fails to develop. Which of the following embryonic layers does this structure originate from?","answers":[{"option":"Endoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Neuroectoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Surface ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Paraxial mesoderm","bool":false},{"option":"Mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following layers of the cornea does not have the ability to regenerate once damaged?","answers":[{"option":"Descemet's membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Bowman's membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Corneal endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Corneal epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is the primary function of the superior oblique?","answers":[{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Abduction","bool":false},{"option":"Extorsion","bool":false},{"option":"Adduction","bool":false},{"option":"Intorsion","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The cells of the thyroid gland, which secrete calcitonin, are derived from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Ultimobranchial body","bool":true},{"option":"Second pharyngeal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal cleft","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A child is brought to the emergency room with an injury to the nasal septum. Which of the following bones are most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal bones only","bool":false},{"option":"Cribriform plate of ethmoid and vomer","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid and vomer","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and nasal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and frontal bones","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following is the correct term for age-related hearing loss?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"A child suffers from a lesion of the nasociliary ganglion. Which of the following nerves supplies the preganglionic parasympathetic fibers to this ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Nerve to inferior oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries is a terminal branch of the right common carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal carotid artery","bool":true}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following muscles of the larynx is involved in the abduction of the vocal cords?","answers":[{"option":"Cricothyroid","bool":false},{"option":"Vocalis","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse arytenoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior cricoarytenoid","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral cricoarytenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies preganglionic parasympathetic nerve fibers to the otic ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Short ciliary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Auricutemporal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following disorders requires surgical removal?","answers":[{"option":"Acoustic neuroma","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperacusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Meningitis","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The pulse of the facial artery can be palpated over the anteroinferior angle of which of the following muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Masseter","bool":true},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":false},{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Orbicularis oris","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticus major","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following vessels is most commonly involved in the setting of an epidural hematoma?","answers":[{"option":"Emissary veins","bool":false},{"option":"Middle meningeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior meningeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Dural venous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior meningeal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following arteries is most likely to be damaged in an injury to the subclavian triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"External carotid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Third part of subclavian artery","bool":true},{"option":"Third part of vertebral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"The hyoid bone develops from which of the following embryological structures?","answers":[{"option":"First and second pharyngeal arches","bool":false},{"option":"First and second pharyngeal pouches","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth and sixth pharyngeal arches","bool":false},{"option":"Second and third pharyngeal arches","bool":true},{"option":"Second and third pharyngeal pouches","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2022","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the sensory innervation of the superior laryngeal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx below the vocal cords","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cords only","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior wall of larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall of larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx above the vocal cords","bool":true}]}]
export default arr